Says it again, cut off from the end of
Daniel. What is the Apocrypha? A certain
group of books of the Bible that used to
be included but ain't in your Bible
today. What was in it? Why did the
church take it out? Well, to understand
this, you got to do a little digging in
the church history. The Apocrypha used
to come standard in all Bibles. The
Council of Hippo in 393 and the Council
of Carthage in 397 reaffirmed and
included them in all standard
literature. First decisive removal
didn't come till 1546 at the Council of
Trent when the Catholic Church removed
the entire Apocrypha and listed the
books of the Bible you have today as
canonical scripture and excluded
everything else. Martin Luther and the
Protestants saw it a little bit
different. In his 1534 edition of the
Bible, he listed the Apocrypha as not
equal to holy scripture but good and
useful to read. In my mind, it's just a
book. Why wouldn't you leave it in there
for people to read it and make their own
decisions? So, I did a little digging.
Here's a hint. It has a lot to do with
the holy land of Israel Palestine. Let's
start at the beginning. First Esdras, as
you can see, it talks about King David,
Israel, the Levites. This one is
excluded because they said it was a
redundant variety of canonical [music]
scripture. Wisdom of Solomon, written
about 100 BC, excluded because it was
written in Greek, not Hebrew.
Ecclesiasticus, written about 180 BC,
excluded because it was not in the
Jewish Bible. Book of Baruch was written
by the prophet Jeremiah's scribe and it
was excluded because it was not in the
Jewish Bible. The History of Susanna, it
even says right here, set apart from the
beginning of Daniel because it is not in
the Hebrew. This Bible was written in
1812, 214 years ago. They they kind of
say the quiet part out loud. think
anybody noticed. Maybe we notice it now.
I take real issue with the First Book of
Maccabees [music] because this is a
historical account of a Jewish revolt
that happened about 160 BC and they
excluded it because it wasn't in the
Jewish Bible and because they said it
was written about 100 BC, which is crazy
because the earliest book of the New
Testament was Mark and that was written
about 50 years after Jesus died, which
is about the same time period of
Maccabees. The Book of Manasseh is
excluded because it was not in the
Hebrew canon. Lastly, the Destruction of
Bel and the Dragon. It says it again,
cut off from the end of Daniel. Why?
Because it was not in the Hebrew canon
again. And not to get off topic, but
they tell us dragons aren't real, right?
But dinosaurs are. What is a dinosaur? A
large reptile. What is a dragon? A large
reptile. You ain't seen the skin on none
of these. How do you know a dragon and a
dinosaur ain't the same thing? Valid
point. Why did they take it out? I'm not
sure, but I've identified a common
thread. It seems that these guys right
here are always behind the scenes
pulling the strings. Is the Christian
church doing it? But only because it was
not in the Jewish Bible. These guys
right here own the media, the banks, and
all the adult film sites. I'm not sure
why these guys didn't want the Apocrypha
in your Bible. I'm also not sure why
they took Palestine out of the Holy
Land, but I'm fixing to put these things
online so we can all read them and
decipher them together because they some
in the game.